Marcos Díaz Oliva

Madrid, España · Linkedin · contact@diazoliva.com

Initial experience in real development and team management projects. I led Backend development at Valuat, achieving up to a 50% improvement in endpoint performance compared to the previous technology and up to 30% in database calls. As a project manager, I provide service to two General Sub-Directorates, managing teams from 3 different companies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Ministry of Housing and Urban Agenda

Madrid, Spain

IT Project Manager

October 2024-Present

- I coordinate 4 work teams from 3 different companies in development, maintenance, and support, serving 2 General Sub-Directorates.
- I contribute to process improvement by implementing methodologies that allow greater control and efficiency in development, support, and maintenance tasks across different teams.
- I manage necessary actions for system maintenance in collaboration with the systems and communications specialized team.
- I analyze current tools and solutions to identify improvements to be implemented in the systems, mainly related to performance and user experience.
- I design reports that offer a practical general overview of each of the managed IT systems and teams.
- I create statistics using Google Analytics as part of the system management, with annualized information and custom reports.

Valuat Madrid, Spain

BackEnd Developer

October 2021–February 2023

- I implemented the Scrum work methodology with two-week sprints, enabling greater efficiency and development speed.
- I improved the efficiency of the BackEnd system by up to 35% compared to the previous system, through analysis and design.

PROJECTS

Web Test Service Madrid, Spain

Laravel, PHP, MySQL, MongoDB

November 2023-June 2024

Web Scripting for Data Statistics

Python, Xampp, MySQL

December 2020-September 2021

EDUCATION

CARLOS III UNIVERSITY OF MADRID

Madrid, Spain

Madrid, España

Computer Engineering

September 2022

Honors: High Distinction in Operating Systems Design, Security Engineering, and Visual Development Methodology.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Native Spanish. Fluent in English.